

Joshua Jainga

253-347-8441 jjainga@gmail.com Sammamish, WA 98075

WEBSITES

linkedin.com/in/joshuajainga github.com/jjainga portfile.herokuapp.com

Summary

Full Stack Developer leveraging economics and operations management background to help solve complex problems to improve user experience. Quick to learn, integrate and teach new knowledge to benefit the team I am supporting. I am excited to continue to grow my skills to build a better experience for everyone.

Projects

Covid-19 Resource page: https://jjainga.github.io/Covid-19-Resource-Page/

 Collaborated with a team to create a Covid-19 resource app using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and utilized Microsoft's Bing Covid-19 data API. The application lets users see real-time changes in Covid statistics and look up the closest Covid-19 testing centers.

Personify: https://personify-personality-quiz.herokuapp.com/

• Created the schema and backend routes for the application Personify, using MySql, Javascript, and Sequelize. This application allows users to take a quiz to find out their personality archetype.

Satsop Bulb Farm: https://satsopbulbfarm.herokuapp.com/

 Created the schema and collaborated with a team on all the routes needed using a NoSQL MongoDB database. Integrated the PayPal API to allow for online purchases and created an order management system use React to allow the client to track orders and complete orders easily.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS
- Javascript
- Node.js
- MySQL
- Sequelize
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- React
- jQuery
- Python
- VBA
- RESTful API
- Strategic planning
- Knowledge of performance tracking

- Outstanding communication skills
- Customer and vendor relations
- Supervisory role background
- Ability to write reports
- Safety protocol
- Staff supervision
- Employee development
- Schedule management
- Supervision and training
- Purchasing and planning
- Sound judgment
- Performance improvements
- Cost analysis and savings
- Cross-functional team management

EXPERIENCE

Operations Area Manager II

Amazon BFI4 Fulfillment Center Feb 2019 to Current

- Assist in the development of new area managers/process assistants in the outbound department. Leads department meetings amongst peers to discuss weekly changes and metrics
- Create a learning curve performance calculator with VBA to identify areas of
 opportunity per associate in the chuting/pack department by showing percent to
 labor plan, week-over-week performance, and the trend for the current shift.
 Resulting data inform targeted performance coaching for department managers.

- Create hourly shift tracker with VBA to assist in the ad hoc reporting of all
 outbound department's metrics. Resulting data identify opportunities in the
 current labor plan and show relative performance in day-over-day and week-overweek.
- Create purchase order requisitions for materials to better associates' work life.
- Track quarterly shift metrics to identify areas of opportunity to meet volume and through-put-hour shift goals.
- Cross-functional collaboration to ensure success in meeting customer's order deadlines and critical pool times.
- Create ad hoc reporting tools to identify productivity opportunities (performance levels of 80% or below) to drive performance.
- Determine team productivity needs and work with other Area Managers to balance shift labor needs.
- Partner with Associates to ensure compliance and consistency are present across the team, and follow-up with corrective action if necessary.
- Supported regional branches with turnaround management processes, increasing organization and efficiency to enhance profitability.
- Recruited and trained Tier 1 and 3 employees to enable adherence to common standards and procedures.
- Verified adherence to OSHA and internal safety standards to minimize risks and enhance workplace safety.
- Educated employees on corporate policy and procedure compliance to facilitate improved operations outcomes.

Seasonal Procurement Operations Analyst

Amazon BFI4 Fulfillment Center Aug 2018 to Feb 2019

- Create reports analyzing trends of spending per blanket purchase order to evaluate potential cost savings and present to Sr. Ops.
- Initiate and lead a cost-saving project in collaboration with Sr. Ops and finance team, saving \$120K annually.
- Take part in discussions with Sr. Ops on barriers for Associates and provide support with solutions.
- Build and manage vendor relationships; negotiate/facilitate vendor proposals for site projects.
- Deep Dive in data of vendor spending history to determine future budgets.
- Track account payable holds to find the root cause of issues and execute resolutions.
- Resolve a standard of 80% account payable holds weekly (six weeks of 100% resolution).
- Facilitate communication between supporting vendors and Amazon to provide a safe, clean, and efficient work facility.
- Developed innovative financial controls system to optimize accounting processes.
- Analyzed operational performance to identify pain-points and provided actionable solutions to management.

Non-Inventory Receiver

Amazon BFI4 Fulfillment Center Nov 2017 to May 2018

- Developed an unloading process that increased productivity by 20% per unload, resulting in an additional 365 unloads per year.
- Maintain consistent workflow throughout the building by prioritizing standard work against the needs of other departments.
- Compared shipment contents with paperwork to support inventory accuracy and records management.
- Performed inspections of shipment contents, verifying accuracy against invoices and manifests.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Full Stack Development: Full Stack Development

University of Washington Nov 2020

Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Science: Economics

Eastern Washington University Jul 2015

Cheney, WA

- Honors Recognition International Economic Society Study Abroad Global City Hong Kong
- Minor in Decision Science

Associate of Arts: Direct Transfer

Bellevue College Jul 2012

Bellevue, WA